

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211









Technology Manager seeking roles in Service Delivery Lead , Technologic Management Risk Management, Change Management, Release Management, Boot, Microservices, GitHub, Maven, Jenkins, Docker, Rest-API, SOAP, Ansible

Scripting, Nagios, AWS-DEVOPS, AWS-SYSOPS

Total Experience: 16 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Notice Period: 1 Month

Highest Degree: MCA[Computers]

Current Designation: Technology Manager -IT

Current Company: NIIT Technologies

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming Maintenance

Role: Product Mar

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

 $\label{thm:constraints} \textit{Key Skills:} \ \textit{Technology Manager}, \ \textit{Service Delivery Lead}, \ \textit{Change Management}, \ \textit{Release}$

Wanagement, GitHub, Waven, Jenkins, Docker, Rest-API, SOAP, Ansible Scripting, Nagios, AWS-DEVOPS, AWS-SYSOPS

Verified : Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: Jan-Mar 2021 Last Modified: Jan-Mar 2021

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

Enterprise IT Leader offering over 15 years of success leading diversified IT products: Master's in computer Applications; 8 years of Product Delivery Management and Product Strategy

Business Strategist: Plan and Implement Product Delivery Solutions for 500+ Million USD programs & projects aligning with critical Business goals; Vendor Management, Resource Management, IT Simplification, Business Enablement & Growth Management/Engagement: Product Management comprising Process Management, People Management, SecDevOps & Automation, IT Modernization, Capacity planning, Risk Management, Change Management, Release Management Communication & Innovations: leverage technical, business and financial acumen to communicate effectively to ideate patents and build in-house efficiency tools within the Organisation

Work Experience

NIIT Technologies as Technology Manager -IT

Aug 2017 to Till Date

Handled large programs spanning for 2 years with a Business value of over \$500Mn

Led by example in creating patentable ideas, build in house efficiency tools, publishing white papers and in winning the Hackathon Events both within the org and outside as well

Built a System to track and approve team member skills and expertises and rolled out to 4000+ Team Members, this can be leveraged an input for Capacity Planning

Managed Critical Consumer Lending Applications and driven the Enterprise Modernization & Simplification & Risk

Management Programs in Consumer Lending

Piloted to initiate the CI/CD within the Group and achieve faster and qualitative delivery

Playing a key role in driving the critical programs of Credit Cards, Home

Soluion Delivery of the enhancements and rewrite of the Applications within Consumer Lending Technology Partnered with HR to define People Competencies & Goals at all levels

Oracle India Pvt Ltd as Principla Software Engineer

Dec 2006 to Aug 2017

Preparation & review of specifications - requirements and design as applicable Ownership of a module/functionality Development of OOAD and UML Diagrams Preparation of Low-Level Design Documents.

Focus-Tech India Pvt Ltd as Software Developer

Sep 2004 to Aug 2006

Created Persistence and Logging framework using Hibernate and Spring Frameworks Represented the Organization for PCMM Level 5 Assessment Development of OOAD and UML Diagrams Build and Release Management - Automation and Integration with CruiseControl, Ant

Important

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: BCA (Computers) from Madras University in 2001 PG: MCA (Computers) from Madras University in 2004

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
Angular, JSF, Primefaces		
spring boot, microservices		
GitHub, Maven, Jenkins		
Selenium, uDeploy, Docker		
Apache, Tomcat, websphere		
Weblogic, Rest-API, SOAP		
JSON		
AWS, Oracle OIC		
JIRA, NewRelic Confluence, HOGAN		

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient	✓	✓	✓
Telugu	Expert	✓	✓	✓
Hindi	Proficient	✓	✓	✓

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent
Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.